We will now go through all of the prerequisites that you need to install before you can start developing
your microservices.
Let's have a look at the tools and technologies that you will need thereafter.
I will provide you with links where you can download each of the respective tools and technologies.
Importantly, I've uploaded a file in the resources section under this lecture that contains all of
these download links and Docker commands.
The first thing that you are going to need is the dot net SDK.
I will be using the dot net six SDK, which was the latest stable release at the time of this recording.
Then you will also need an ID or code editor such as via code, Visual Studio or Rider.
Now I'm a massive fan of VS Code and I love the command line interface.
So if you want to follow along you can go full vs code.
But I know that Visual Studio is probably the most popular idea amongst dot net developers and with
the release of Visual Studio 2022, it is much faster, looks better and loads quicker when you open
up a solution.
Or you can go for Git Brains Rider.
Then we will install postmen to test our APIs.
We will also install Docker to make our installation of Apache, Kafka, MongoDB and Microsoft SQL Server
much simpler.
And for those of you that have never used Docker, it'll give you some basic exposure to Docker and
see how you can run each of these infrastructure services as containers in Docker.
You can get the DOT net six SDK from dot net dot Microsoft dot com forward slash n us forward slash
download forward slash dot net version 6.0.
But please look out for the latest version.
If dot net six is no longer the latest version.
When you watch this video, you will see that the dot net SDK can now run on Windows, Linux or Mac
and dot net six and greater pretty much builds on dot net CO OC.
And then once you've installed your dot net SDK, you can open up your terminal or command prompt or
PowerShell and then type dot net dash dash version to see which version of the dot net SDK you have
installed.
And now for the ID or code editor, you can download verse code from code dot Visual Studio dot com
for download and Visual Studio Community Edition from Visual Studio dot Microsoft.com Forward slash
V is forward slash community and then rider from WW W Jedburgh brains dot com forward slash rider.
Now if you are going to use vs code, you should know that VS code is nothing more than a text editor
without extensions.
Extensions are the things that turns vs code into a powerful code editor.
Now if you use VS code, you will need three extensions.
Firstly, the C shop for Visual Studio code extension.
You can get it from Marketplace dot Visual Studio dot com forward slash items item name equals image
net tools C shop or for a much more convenient way to install extensions, open up your VS Code Code
Editor and then go ahead and click on the extensions tab on the left.
Then you can search for C shop, click on the top C Shop extension.
You'll see that it is C shop by Microsoft with more than 16 million downloads.
Then go ahead and click on install.
All right.
The next extension that you are going to need is the nugget package manager.
You can get it from Marketplace dot Visual Studio dot com.
Items item name jam rock dot vsco nugget package manager or in verse code.
It's much simpler to search for the extensions from the extensions marketplace.
You can type NuGet package manager and then click on the top one there.
And again, go ahead and install the extension.
And then finally we are going to use the SQL Server SQL VTS code extension for connecting to Microsoft
SQL Server.
And this will essentially be our client tools.
You can get it from Marketplace dot Visual Studio dot com items item name equals RMS, MSC, SQL dot
SQL or again much simpler within this code type Ms. SQL.
Then click on the top one.
There you'll see SQL Server and in brackets MSC SQL by Microsoft.
And then you can go ahead and click Install again.
Next, you need to go ahead and install Postman.
You can get it from w w post msn.com forward slash downloads.
Next we need to install Docker now.
If you haven't used Docker or Kubernetes before, you are in for a surprise.
You can download Docker for Mac or windows from WW W dot dotcom forward slash products forward slash
Docker desktop.
I've also added multiple links for downloading Docker on Linux.
I'm not going to read out all of them, but you can find these download links in the Prerequisites Installation
file that I've attached in the resources section of this lecture.
And once you have installed Docker, you can go ahead and open up your Terminal Command prompt or PowerShell
and run the Docker dash, dash version command.
And as you can see, I am running Docker version 20.10 point seven built if 0f350.
Importantly, you have to start all Docker commands in Linux with sudo, which refers to running commands
in Linux with security privileges or as a super user.
The equivalent in Windows will be running command prompt or PowerShell as administrator.
The first command that we can run is Sudo Docker P s to list all of our running containers.
But as you can see, there are no containers to deploy to Docker yet.
We are now going to run a few of our prerequisites as Docker containers instead of installing them directly
onto our computers in the traditional fashion.
But before we do that, let's create a Docker network which will enable our microservices to communicate
with Apache, Kafka, MongoDB and Microsoft SQL Server, which we are going to install as Docker containers
in the next few lectures to create our Docker network.
Let's run the following command Docker.
Network.
Create.
Dash Dash Attachable, which will allow us to attach Docker containers later to this network.
Dash DX To specify the driver of the network.
Let's specify the driver as bridge and then let's call our network, my Docker network.
You can use a better name if you want.
Hit Enter and then our Docker network has successfully been created and then let's run Docker Network
Ellis to list all of our Dr. Networks on our Dr. Host.
And there you can see the newly created my Dr. Network.
Okay.
Now we are ready to install Apache, Kafka, MongoDB and Microsoft SQL Server as Docker containers in
the following few lectures.