The next thing that you need to do is to install Docker compose.
We are going to use Docker Compose to run Kafka and Apache Zookeeper in Docker as containers.
Navigate to
docs.docker.com/compose/install.
If you scroll down to the install compose section, you'll notice that there are instructions on how
to install Docker.
Compose on Mac.
Windows.
Windows Server.
Linux.
And there are also alternative install options that you can check out.
I've already installed Docker compose, so I will advise you to navigate to this page and make sure
to follow the instructions on how to install Docker.
Compose on your machine and then once you have installed Docker compose you can run the Docker compose
dash dash version command.
And as you can see, my Docker compose version is 1.20 7.4.
The next thing that we need to do is to run Apache Kafka in Docker using Docker, Compose Notice the
Docker compose file format that contains a file version, version 3.4, and then we are specifying two
services.
Firstly, Apache, Zookeeper, now Apache Zookeeper is very important because the Kafka brokers, which
I will tell you about a little later, are stateless.
And Zookeeper is responsible for managing the Kafka cluster and also for electing the lead broker.
But we will only add a single broker.
So that's why we have the Zookeeper service.
There you can see the image, which is the Docker image, the restart policy, which is set to always
in other words, if there are any exceptions, it should always restart the ports.
It's running on port 2181.
That is the external port and 2181 internal port.
That is the Docker volume next, which is specified as Zookeeper underscore data that would be the directory
on the host.
And then after the colon forward slash bitnami would be the mapped folder within the container.
And then there's an environmental variable allow anonymous login equals.
Yes.
And then we have our Kafka instance.
There we have the image Bitnami forward slash Kafka, that is the Docker image.
Bitnami is the repository, and Kafka is the image name the Port 9092 External internal restart policy
always as well volumes.
Kafka underscore data that is a persistent volume and persistent volumes are especially important with
Docker because if we stored our data in the container, we will lose it.
Every time that the Docker container is recreated.
Then we have a couple of environmental variables.
Kafka, Zookeeper Connect.
There we specify the Zookeeper service name Colon, the port name, and obviously that's set to 2181.
Allow plaintext Listener equals yes.
Kafka Listener Plain Text Port 9092.
Then Kafka advertise listeners equals plaintext colon forward slash forward slash localhost port 9092.
And then we say the Kafka service depends on Zookeeper.
And down below we are just specifying our persistent volumes and that the zookeeper and Kafka containers
should also belong to the network.
Now I have created a Docker folder under my home directory and created a file called Docker Hyphen Compose
Dot Yml.
Make sure that you use that exact name when you do the same.
Now I have already copied the contents of this Docker compose file and you can get a copy of this Docker
compose file from the resources section under this lecture.
Now if we open up the Docker compose file, you will notice the contents matches the ones I've just
shown you.
Then change the directory to where you have created the Docker compose file and then run Docker hyphen.
Compose space up space dash D.
Now Dash D is very important because it will run it as detached.
If you do not add dash D, it will run Kafka and Apache Zookeeper in your terminal session.
And as you can see there, it starts to download the zookeeper image.
And then it starts downloading the Kafka image.
And then when it has completed downloading the Docker images and there you can see that the Zookeeper
and Kafka Docker containers have been successfully created.
So let's run Docker.
PS And there you can see that our Kafka and Zookeeper containers are running in Docker.