The next thing that we are going to deploy in Docker is MongoDB.
There you can see the Docker run command that we are going to use to deploy MongoDB.
So let's start with the command sudo docker run dash 80 dash dx for detach again.
Our container name.
Mongo hyphen container.
Then we'll use the standard MongoDB ports 20 7017.
Internal and external.
And we will also put the mongo container in the same network.
As well as specify the restart policy.
As always, nowadays, V allows us to specify a Docker volume now in order to be able to save or persist
data and also to share data between containers.
Docker came up with the concept of volumes.
Quite simply, volumes are directories of files that are outside of the default union file system and
exist as normal directories and files on the host file system.
So this is not in the container itself because if it was, we would lose the data every time the container
is recreated.
And that is something that we want the recreation of containers.
Okay.
Now the final thing is just to add the image name, which is Mongo, and then also specify the latest
version.
You will see that the Mongo latest image is being pulled from the Docker hub repo.
Okay.
And now it has been deployed again.
We can run pseudo docker PS and then you will see Kafka Zookeeper and now the mongo container deployed.
Okay.
I have installed Rainbow three T as the client tools as indicated in the slide, but you can use the
mongo shell or any other mongo client that you prefer.
But if you are using Rainbow three TX like I am, you can go ahead and create a new connection.
I'm going to call the connection Mongo in Docker.
And in brackets local you can keep the addresses local and then the port as the default port 270174.
Now we are not going to enable authentication.
Okay click on test there you can see that rober three ttx successfully connects to our mongodb container.
Okay.
Now if you connect you will see that we only have the default system databases.