I'm now going to show you how to deploy Microsoft SQL Server to Docker.
Now we are going to use Microsoft SQL Server for our database.
So there you can see the Docker run command to deploy Microsoft SQL Server as a container in Docker.
Now you can also use Docker Compose like we have done when we deployed Kafka.
Now I'm just going to use the Docker run command.
So say pseudo Docker run RD for detached and then specify the container name as SQL hyphen container.
And then let's say that our SQL container should also belong to my Docker network.
And then we can set our restart policy as always.
And then we need to add a few environmental variables.
We can say accept, underscore EU a end user license agreement and then say equals Y for yes.
And then another environmental variable is a underscore password and that will be the system administrator
password.
Let's make it strong password.
Zero two but I'm going to use dollar DT or zero in G capital S at P at SSW zero or d02.
Now, you might argue that's not a strong password at all, but my intention here is to tell you to
use a strong password for your password, and then another environmental variable.
And then in quotes there.
SQL underscore p id equals express.
And close the quotes.
And then let's set up port dash p.
One four, three three internal and 1433 external port.
That is the standard Microsoft SQL Server port.
And then we need to specify the image name.
You can say MSI R dot Microsoft.
Dot com.
Forward Slash Aims sequel.
Forward slash server colon.
2017 dash latest dash.
One two.
Hit Enter and then you will see that it will start to download the Microsoft SQL Server 2017 image from
the Docker Hub Repo.
Okay, so now you can see that it has been successfully downloaded and deployed to Docker.
So let's run the Docker command again, pseudo Docker piece and then you'll see there that we also now
have a SQL container with the Mongo container and our Kafka and Zookeeper containers.
Now if we go back to our slides there, we need to download client tools to connect to our Microsoft
SQL Server database.
And you can download the SQL Management Studio, which is probably the most popular Microsoft SQL Server
client tools.
Or if you are using VS code like I am, you can install an extension for SQL Server.
So I'm going to open up my VTS code and then you can head over to the extensions tab and then type SQL
Server.
And then you'll find it right at the top.
There it is by Microsoft with almost 5 million downloads.
Then you can hit install.
And then once it has been installed, you will see a SQL Server icon just below there and then we can
go ahead and add a connection to our SQL container.
So click on Add Connection and then for the server name, type, local host or your domain or IP address
that you are using, then I'm not going to add a database name that's optional.
Select SQL Login as the authentication type.
The username is a.
And the password, our strong S.A. password, which is dollar tr0 in g is capital at P, capital at
s is w zero or d zero to hit enter safe password.
Yes, you can add a profile name, but I'm not going to turn in the right bottom corner.
You'll see my SQL profile created and connected.
And then there on the left hand side, it shows that we are successfully connected to our SQL container.