Now that we've installed all of our prerequisites, it's time for us to do our basic project setup for
our microservices solution.
Okay, so let's start by creating two folders for our microservices projects.
The first we can call queries is and then creates.
Another one is m dash post where SM is an abbreviation for social media going to the SM post folder.
And then let's create two folders, one called post dot cmd and then creates another one that we can
call post query.
We will create all of our projects that relates to the post command API in the post dot cmd folder and
all of the projects that relate to the post query API in the post or query folder.
Then if you are using VS code like I am, you can click on open folder and then go to the directory
where you've created your C queries is and is in post folder and click on open.
There you can see the two folders that we have just created as well as the post or CMD and post or query
folders within the SM post directory.
Okay.
Now I'm going to use CLI to create all of the dot net projects.
You can do that by changing directory and going into the secure restore is folder and then we can say
dot net new and then say class lib.
This is short for class library.
And then dash oh four output and then let's give our project a name, let's call it C, Q or ESCO.
If you use the dash.
Oh, it'll create a directory using the name that you've just supplied.
Okay, hit enter and then you'll see the security score project within the secure is directory.
And there if you open up the CSP file, you'll see that we are using dot net six.
Okay.
So let's go back.
CD Space dot dot going back one directory.
And then we can change directory into the same post folder and then we can say dot net new Iselin.
So we want to create a solution file within the in post folder and it will actually use the name of
the folder for the solution for ASEM dash post n.
Okay, so now we can create our post command projects.
So let's seed into the post cmd folder and then we can say dot net new web API instead of class lib
this time dash.
Oh and then let's call our web API project post dot cmd dot API.
As you can see there, it was successfully created in the post dot cmd folder.
The next project that we want to create is a project for our domain layer.
So let's say dot net new class lib.
Dash Oh, and then let's call it post dot cmd dot domain.
And as you can see there, we now have two projects for our post command API and it is the post at CMD
API and they you also see the domain and then we need to create one more project for our post command
microservice and that is for our infrastructure layer.
So let's say dot net new class lib.
Dash Oh, and then let's call it post dot cmd dot infrastructure.
And now you can see that we have all of our projects that we need for post command, microservice and
API domain and infrastructure project.
Alright, let's go back one folder seed, dot, dot and then let's change directory into post or query.
We are going to do similar for the query microservice now.
So let's start with our API project.
So let's say dot net new web API.
Dash.
Oh, and then let's call it post dot query dot API.
And there you can see that it's been created.
And then let's create a project for our domain layer dot net new class lib dash oh and then post dot
query dot domain.
Right.
So if we expand that, you can see we have our API and the main project and then we also need to create
a infrastructure project for the post query microservice.
So let's say dot net new clos lib dash oh and let's call it post dot query dot infrastructure.
And as you can see there, we now have all three projects that we need for the post query API, an API
layer, a domain layer and an infrastructure layer.
Okay.
So let's go ahead and clear our terminals and then we are going to add all of these projects to our
solution file.
So let's go back one directory seed, dot, dot, and then we in the ACM post directory, then we can
say dot net ACL in.
ED And then we first want to add the Crisco project.
To do that, we can say dot dot.
So it essentially goes one back forward slash secures dash is you can use tab to auto complete forward
slash secure restore core forward slash secure restore coach see as.
And if you open up your post or excel in file, you'll see that the Secure Restore Core Project was
just added to the solution file.
All right.
Next, let's go ahead and add all of our post CMD projects.
You can say dot net SL in add post thought, cmd forward slash post or cmd API forward slash post or
cmd API dot c is proj.
And as you can see there, we now have the post cmd and post cmd dot API projects added to the solution
file.
Then we can do the same dot net isolating add post that cmd post at cmd domain and in the post that
cmd domain CSS file.
And it's also added to the solution file.
And then let's go ahead and add our last post dot cmd project.
We can say dot net SL in add post or cmd for slash post dot cmd that infrastructure forward slash post
dot cmd infrastructure dot CSS proj.
And as you can see there, we now have all of our post seamed projects added to our solution file.
Next, let's start by adding a post query project so you can say dot net sl n ad and then post dot query
forward slash post or query dot api forward slash post dot query dot api dot c proj.
Then let's add a domain project dot net sl in add.
Post or query.
Post dot query dot main.
Forward slash posted query domain that sees proj.
And then a final post query project, the infrastructure project, let's say dot net SL in ad and then
say post dot query forward slash post dot query dot infrastructure forward slash post dot query dot
infrastructure dot is proj.
And now we have added all of our projects to the solution file.
We've got the security dot co, the post ot cmd, the post dot cmd dot API, the post dot cmd dot domain,
the post cmd dot infrastructure the post dot query the post dot query dot API the post r query dot domain
and the post dot query dot infrastructure projects added to our solution file.
So this concludes the basic setup of our microservices projects.
In the next lecture we are going to add all of the project references.