In the previous lecture we created a microservices projects.
In this lecture we are going to add our project references.
We will start by adding project references to our post or CMD API project.
We will add three project references, starting with adding a reference to the C crystal core project.
So you can add a project reference as follows you can say dot net add and then let's say post dot cmd
forward slash post dot.
Seemed dot ap.
Forward slash posts at cmd dot api css proj.
And they say reference.
So you're saying add a reference to post or cmd api dot c.
S bridge and then say dot dot to go back one directory and then say see, Chris Dash is forward slash
secure restore core four slash secure.
Restore code c is proj.
And then you can open up the post at CMD API, the CSS branch file and then you'll see we've added a
project reference for the sea restart core project.
Then we can do similar.
Just going to go ahead and copy everything up into reference and then we can change it ever so slightly.
So this time we want to add a project reference to the domain project.
So you can say add a reference to post dot cmd dot domain.
And then post that candidate domain dot C as proj hit enter.
You'll see it's been added to the CS proj file.
All right.
And then we also want to add a project reference to the infrastructure project so you can just press
up.
And then it'll show the last command.
So let's change that to post the CMD or infrastructure.
And in the CSP watch section they change to post or CMD or infrastructure that C is branch.
And as you can see there in our CSP file, we also now have a project reference to post or cmd dot infrastructure.
Dot C is proj.
All right.
There's actually one more project that I forgot to create in the previous lecture, and that is the
Post Common Project.
And the Post or Comment Project will actually be the project where we add our event objects because
the event objects needs to be shared between the post command and post query APIs.
So before we continue adding our project references, let's say dot net new clause lib.
Dash oh and then just say post dot com.
And so this is from within the post folder.
Right.
And then our post or comment project has been successfully created, as you can see there.
All right.
So we've got the post simply post comment and post query projects within the post folder.
Okay.
So now we actually also want to go ahead and add a reference to the post, that common project.
And let's change that last part to post dot com and food slash post dot com and don't see as much.
And now I've added all of the project references for our post that seemed API.
Okay.
Next up, we want to go ahead and add project references for our domain project so you can see dot net
at post at CMD for slash post that cmd domain for slash post that seemed dot domain dot C as proj reference.
And then we want to add a reference to our security dot com project.
So it's dot dot forward slash secure dash is for slash security score for slash security stat code.
See, as much as you can see there, we now have successfully added a project reference to our security
dot co project for our domain project.
Now we need to add one more reference for our domain project and that's the post, that common project.
So press up and then let's change the port of to the reference to post common.
Forward slash post dot com and dot c is branch.
And then we also need to go ahead and add some project references for our post dot cmd dot infrastructure
project.
As you can see, we have no project references as yet.
So let's say dot net ed post that seemed forward slash posts that seemed the infrastructure for slash
post that seem needed infrastructure dot C as branch reference.
Then we want our first reference to be to the dot com project dot dot forward slash security stash is
for slash security.
That code for slash security is code C is branch and then you can press up.
And they changed the section after reference to posts that seemed for slash posts that seemed domain
for slash posts at cmd domain.
See us branch because we want to reference the domain project.
Alright, now we have the two project references that we need for the infrastructure project and that's
all the project references we need for the post or CMD project.
Now we also want to go ahead and add a single project reference for the post or common project.
Okay.
Now the most common project will only depend or reference the security stored core project.
So let's say dot net ed post or common forge slash post or comment or C s bridge reference and then
dot dot forward slash security stash is for slash security taco food slash security code or CS punch
hit enter.
And there you can see we now have a project reference to the C crystal core project for the post common
project.
Okay.
The next project that we will be adding references for is the Post Query API project.
So go ahead and open it, see us branch file and then we'll start by adding a reference to the C Cresco
project so we can say dot net, add post or query for slash post query or API for slash postal query.
That API dot c is branch reference dot dot forward slash security stash is forward slash KIRSTEN code
for slash security dot coded C branch.
Now, if you don't like the command line, this is probably very tedious and you would rather add all
your project references and Visual Studio.
Okay.
So we've added the security start code project reference.
So now we want to go ahead and add a project reference to the post dot query dot domain project.
So just press up.
And then after the reference change to post dot query forward slash post dot query dot domain.
Forward slash post dot query, dot domain, dot CS approach.
Okay.
Now we have a project reference to the domain project.
Then go ahead and add a reference to the infrastructure project.
So again, press up and then change the section after reference to post or query dot infrastructure
for slash post that created infrastructure dot C approach.
And then the final reference that we need is to post on Common C post or Common Forward slash post or
common dot C is project.
Now we have all of the project references for the post query API Project Security Start core query dot
domain query that infrastructure and post comment.
Let's clear our terminals for some space there and then we are going to add the project references for
the post query domain project.
You can again press up.
And then we'll change it to post or query dot domain.
And then also the see is spot to post dot query dot domain dot C is proj.
And then after the reference, we will add the C crystal co project first.
Dot dot forward slash security's dash is secure, restore core and then secure a store code at approach.
So as you can see there, we have that project reference in our CS profile up there.
Then we also want to go ahead and add a project reference to the post dot Common Project.
So press up and then change the section after the reference to post dot com and forward slash post that
common that C is approach.
And that is the two references that we need for the post query domain project.
And then finally, let's add the project references for the Post Query Infrastructure Project.
Press up all the way to the way the security store code project was added to the domain project.
And then we can easily change post or query dot domain to post that query dot infrastructure forward
slash post dot query dot infrastructure, dot CS branch.
And the section after reference stays the same.
And then we also want to add a project reference to the query dot domain project.
So you can say post dot, query, forward, slash post or query dot domain forward slash post or query
dot domain dot CSS proj.
Right.
Those are the only two references we need for the infrastructure project.
Okay.
So now we have added all of the project references that we need.
In the next lecture we will be adding all of our NuGet packages.