We are now going to add the required NuGet packages to all of our microservices projects.
For those of you who are unfamiliar with Nugget, it is the official package manager for the DOT Net
Developer Platform and Nugget package is basically a compiled library with some descriptive metadata.
It is a mechanism through which dot net developers can create, share and consume useful code.
We will start by adding the required nugget packages to our security historical project.
You can access the nugget package manager in code by holding down control shift and then pressing P
and then you will see nugget package manager at package.
Click on add package and then it will prompt you for the nugget package name.
So let's type mongo db dot driver.
And then go ahead and click on MongoDB Dot Driver.
And then select the latest version.
At the time of this recording, it was 2.69.1 and then select the Secure Restore Code Project.
And as you can see in our case file, the MongoDB Nugget package was successfully added.
Next, let's add the required nugget packages for a post command infrastructure project.
Again, you can access it by holding control shift and P then click on NuGet Package Manager at package
and then type Confluent.
Scott Kafka.
Okay.
Hit Enter and then select confronted Kafka there and then select the latest version, 1.9.0 and select
post command infrastructure as your project there.
And as you can see there, the confirm that Kafka package was added again click add package this time
search for Microsoft dot extensions, dot options.
We're going to use it to inject our config.
So click on Microsoft dot extensions, dot options and then select version 6.0.0 and click on the Post
Command Infrastructure Project.
Now, the reason I selected 6.0.0 is because it needs to match the target framework, which is dot net
six.
And then let's add another NuGet package.
MongoDB dot driver.
Again, select the latest version.
And then the project infrastructure is proj and that are all the NuGet packages that we need for the
Post Command Infrastructure Project.
Next, let's open up the post query infrastructure projects, see us project file.
And the reason I'm opening it up is just so that you can see that the package references are being added.
So again, hold down control shift and press p.
Click on Ed package.
This time, the first package that we are going to add is Microsoft DOT Entity Framework called SQL
Server.
Select Microsoft in the framework that SQL Server and then select the latest stable release version
6.0.6.
In my case, select the Post Query Infrastructure Project, and that also matches the target framework.
The second nugget package that we are going to add is Microsoft DOT Extensions, DOT hosting.
So like Microsoft or extensions that hosting and the latest stable version 6.0.1.
And it matches the target framework.
And then at another nugget package.
Confluent, but Kafka.
This time we'll use it for the Kafka consumer.
In the command site for the producer.
So again, 1.9.0 is the version and select post query infrastructure as the project.
And that concludes all of the NuGet packages that we need to add for all of our projects.
So we only have NuGet packages in our secure core project and in our infrastructure projects of both
the command and query sites.
Okay.
So now that we've added all of our nugget packages, you can open up your terminal.
And then from within the ACM post directory where our solution file is, let's type dot net restore
and this is to restore all of our packages.
And as you can see there, it has been successfully restored.
In the next lecture, I'm going to show you how you can set up the Lone Star JSON file that will be
used during debugging.