We have one last thing to configure for our microservices projects and that is to set up the launch
date JSON file, which is our DBA configurations for net applications and VS code.
The first thing that we need to do is to again hold down control shift and then click on P and then
go ahead and click on dot net, generate assets for build and debug and then go ahead and select the
post dot cmd API as the main project there.
And then notice the configuration section is an array so you can add multiple debug configurations.
And then importantly, look at the ASP.NET Core environment, which is set to development.
So our default environment will be development.
Importantly, the ASP.NET Core Environment Development will make sure that the app settings DOT development
JSON file gets used during debug, but let's go and add another environmental variable.
ASP.NET Core underscore URLs.
And then let's say the value is HTTP.
Forward slash, forward slash local host and then let it run on port 5010.
You can make it whatever you want.
So when we debug our post command API will run on local host port 5010.
All right, so let's change the name to specifically identify that this is for the post command API.
So let's call it post dot cmd API and then we can go ahead and copy the entire section there.
Like I've mentioned, it's an array.
So we also want a section for our post query API so we can change it to post query API.
And then the program will be post or query.
So that's just where the directory is.
Post the query dot api.
The Ben debug nate 6.0 stays the same and the dll change to post query dot API.
Okay.
And then also the CW dx.
Change that to post dot query dot API as well.
And then let's change our ASP.NET Core URLs environmental variable to 5011.
Okay.
So now if you click on the debug tab, you'll see that we have run and debug and you can select between
post dot, cmd, dot API and post dot query dot API.
This will also allow us to run both simultaneously when we debug our APIs much later.